--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 访问 http://www.cmct.tv<br />
影片压制：风潇潇　字幕调校：风潇潇　招募Q号：76846146<br />
字幕来源：YYeTs字幕组<br />
我奠定大地根基的时候 你在哪里呢？<br />
那时晨星一起歌唱 上帝的众子也都欢呼？<br />
约伯记 第38章:4,7节<br />
Brother...
弟弟<br />
Mother...
母亲<br />
It was they who led me to your door.
是他们把我领到你们的门前<br />
A man's heart has heard two ways through life.
扪心自问 生命之路有两条<br />
The way of nature.
一条是顺从天性 随性而为<br />
And the way of grace.
或是风度高雅 严于律己<br />
You have to choose which one you'll follow.
你要选择属于自己的路<br />
Grace doesn't try to please itself.
要有风度就无法事事顺心<br />
It accepts being slighted, forgotten, disliked.
受到轻视 遗忘和厌恶时要泰然处之<br />
It accepts insults and injuries.
受到侮辱和中伤时要学会接受<br />
Nature only wants to please itself.
天性则需要顺从 需要取悦<br />
Bless our lord this food...
感谢上帝赐予我们食物...<br />
Get others to please it too.
天性悦万物<br />
...loving and faithful service...
爱和一成不变的服务...<br />
It likes to lord it over them.
万物顺天性<br />
...Bless these boys...
保佑我们的孩子...<br />
To have its own way.
方能创其独特之道<br />
It finds reasons to be unhappy.
痛苦可以信手拈来<br />
When all the world is shining around it.
不论周遭世界多么灿烂<br />
And love is smiling through all things.
又或爱正在天地间微笑徜徉<br />
They taught us, that no one who loves the way of grace,
他们教育我们 崇尚高雅举止的人<br />
ever comes to a bad end.
结局都很美好<br />
I will be true to you,
无论发生何事<br />
whatever comes.
我都会向你敞开心房<br />
My son.
我的儿啊<br />
I just want to die. To be with him.
我只想去死 去陪他<br />
He's in God's hands now.
上帝把他接走了<br />
He was in God's hands the whole time.
他从未离开过上帝<br />
Wasn't he?
不是吗<br />
My home.
我的家<br />
My God.
我的上帝<br />
I shall fear no evil.
我什么也不怕了<br />
Fear no evil, for you are with me.
不怕了 因为你在这里陪着我<br />
What did you gain?
你得到了什么呢<br />
Be not far from me, for trouble is near.
别离我太远 危险就在附近<br />
Go on now, we're alright.
快走吧 我们没事儿<br />
We're alright.
我们没事儿<br />
Thank you.
谢谢<br />
Shouldn't have your memories of him.
你应该忘记他<br />
You have to be strong now, and...
你要变坚强<br />
I know, the pain will, it will pass in time.
听我说 痛苦总会过去<br />
You know, it might seem,
这可能<br />
hard, my saying that, but it's true.
并不容易 但确实是真理<br />
I don't want it to.
我不想忘记<br />
Life goes on.
生活总要继续<br />
People pass along.
人总有一死<br />
Nothing stays the same.
没有什么是永恒不变的<br />
You still got the other two.
你还有另外两个儿子啊<br />
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.
上帝先给予后收回<br />
That's the way he is.
这就是他的行事原则<br />
He sends flies to wounds...that he should heal.
该去治愈的伤口 他却往上撒盐<br />
I never got a chance to tell him how sorry I was.
我都没机会说 我有多对不起他<br />
I even...
我甚至<br />
punched himself in the face for no reason.
无缘无故就揍他的脸<br />
You sit next to me at the piano
你弹琴时 我就坐在你旁边<br />
and I criticized where he'd turned the pages.
他一翻琴谱 我就训斥他<br />
I might even feel ashamed.
我甚至觉得羞耻<br />
Why shame?
为什么呢<br />
Poor boy. Poor boy.
可怜的孩子 可怜的孩子<br />
How did you come to me?
你如何来到我的身边<br />
In what shape?
以何种形状<br />
What disguise?
戴着什么样的面具<br />
I see the child I was.
我看到了我小时候<br />
I see my brother.
看到了我弟弟<br />
True.
纯真<br />
Kind.
善良<br />
He died when he was 19.
他十九岁时死了<br />
Just check, this one against this.
再查查 这个和这个有问题<br />
She wants to get back together.
她想复合<br />
But, the chapter's closed, the story's been told.
但是感情都没了 该说的话也说了<br />
What are you gonna do?
你打算怎么办<br />
Experiment.
再试试<br />
When you're young, it's all about your career.
年轻的时候 事业是生活的全部<br />
I just feel like I'm...bumping into walls.
我只是觉得自己...四处碰壁<br />
The world's gone to the dogs,
世界落入了无能之辈手中<br />
people are greedy and keep getting worse.
人们变得贪婪 得寸进尺<br />
I try to get into their hands.
我试图理解他们<br />
Hey dad, I'm sorry I said what I said, I'm...
爸 我刚才不该说那些话的 对不起 我...<br />
Yeah, I think about him every day.
没错 我每天都会想起他<br />
I just shouldn't have said what I did, I'm sorry.
我不该说那些话 对不起<br />
What are you thinking? I know, I know what you did...
你觉得呢 我明白 我明白你那么做...<br />
And only two of those were turned down by client...
只有两个人遭到了客户的否定...<br />
How did I lose you?
我是怎么失去你的<br />
Wandered.
四处游荡<br />
Forgot you.
忘记了你<br />
Find me.
来找我<br />
How did she bear it?
她是怎么熬过来的<br />
Mother.
母亲<br />
Was I false to you?
你觉得我虚伪吗<br />
Lord...
上帝啊<br />
Why?
为什么<br />
Where were you?
你在哪里<br />
Did you know?
你知道吗<br />
Who are we to you?
对你来说我们是什么呢<br />
Answer me.
回答我<br />
We cry to you.
我们向你哭诉<br />
My soul.
我的灵魂<br />
My son.
我的儿子<br />
Hear us.
你来听听啊<br />
Light up my life.
照亮我的生活吧<br />
I search for you.
我追寻着你<br />
My home.
我的家<br />
My child.
我的孩子<br />
You spoke to me through her.
你通过她与我对话<br />
You spoke with me from the sky.
你在天上与我交流<br />
The trees.
那些树<br />
Before I knew I loved you,
在我还不知道我爱你<br />
believed in you.
在我信任你之前<br />
When did you first touch my heart?
你是何时触动了我的心弦<br />
...and manfully to fight under
...呼喊着口号 勇敢坚定的<br />
his banner against sin, the world, and the devil.
抗击罪恶 抗击这个世界 抗击邪恶<br />
跑<br />
We're having Mr. McMander over for dinner.
我们要请麦曼德先生来吃饭<br />
This is a double bidder right on in.
这句话里有两个d音<br />
What's this?
这是什么<br />
- Two alligators. - Two alligators.
- 两头短吻鳄 - 两头短吻鳄<br />
- Kangaroo. - Kangaroo.
- 长颈鹿 - 长颈鹿<br />
Jump. Jump. Jump. Jump.
跳 跳 跳 跳<br />
Sweetheart.
亲爱的<br />
Please.
别这样<br />
I know.
我知道<br />
No! No!
不行 不行<br />
It's mine!
是我的<br />
You found me!
找到我啦<br />
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.
等树长高你早就长大了<br />
Blue far.
一大片的蓝<br />
You.
你<br />
Are you afraid?
害怕吗<br />
Come here.
过来<br />
Come here. Alright, now come back here son,
过来 到这儿来儿子<br />
stay out of there. That's Spencer's yard, okay?
离那远点儿 那是斯潘塞家的院子 知道吗<br />
You see this line?
看见这条线了吗<br />
Let's not cross it, you understand?
别过了界 明白吗<br />
Do you understand?
你明白了吗<br />
Do you see this line? Look it here. Look here.
看见这条线了吗 看这儿 看<br />
Okay, now come back here son. Come on back.
好了 回来儿子 回来<br />
Let's stay out of there.
我们离那儿远点儿<br />
"Now, my dears," said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning,
一天早上 兔奶奶说到 亲爱的<br />
"You may go into the fields or down the lane."
你可以到外面或者巷子里玩儿啦<br />
"Don't go into Mr. Mcgregor's garden."
不过别到麦克格雷戈先生的花园里去<br />
"Your father had an accident there."
你爸爸在那儿出过事<br />
That's where God lives.
那就是上帝住的地方<br />
Goodnight, we'll see you in 5 years.
晚安 我们五年后见<br />
Want to eat a grasshopper?
想吃蚱蜢吗<br />
I found it! I found this old bone!
找到啦 我找到老骨头了<br />
Oh, is that a rock?
是块石头吗<br />
No.
不是<br />
Bless this food to our use.
感谢上帝赐予我们食物<br />
As to your loving and faithful service.
献上我们的爱与一成不变的服务<br />
Make us remindful of those who are in need.
请使我们铭记那些需要帮助的人<br />
Amen.
阿门<br />
Can you pass the butter, please?
请把黄油递过来好吗<br />
Can you pass the butter please sir.
请把黄油递过来好吗 先生<br />
Sir.
先生<br />
- What did you do today? - We went to school.
- 你们今天干什么了 - 去了学校<br />
After that.
之后呢<br />
What about the yard?
院子里呢<br />
Did you put the runners in like I asked?
把滑道按我说的收拾好了吗<br />
Yes.
是的<br />
Yes, sir.
是的 先生<br />
Well, it didn't look like it.
看起来可不像<br />
Yes.
是的<br />
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report.
里斯先生很喜欢杰克的书评<br />
Nobody's asked sweetheart.
没人问你话 亲爱的<br />
You know this.
别老让我说<br />
Crowns!
巅峰之作<br />
勃拉姆斯 第四交响曲 托斯卡尼尼指挥<br />
- Son. - Sir.
- 儿子 - 先生<br />
Reach me my lighter.
把我的打火机拿来<br />
Haven't you forgotten something?
你是不是忘了什么啊<br />
Do you love your father?
你爱你的父亲吗<br />
Yes, sir.
爱 先生<br />
...and they went off to look for Kaa the Rock Python.
他们出发去找大蟒蛇克尔<br />
They found him stretched out
他们发现蟒蛇沐浴在下午的阳光中<br />
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun,
趴在温暖的岩礁上<br />
admiring his beautiful new coat.
欣赏着自己美丽的新外衣<br />
Who do you love most?
我们三个里面你最爱谁<br />
I love you all three the same.
一样爱<br />
Tell us a story from before we can remember.
给我们讲一个我们没听过的故事吧<br />
He went for a ride in a plane once.
你爸爸曾经开过一次飞机<br />
It was a graduation present.
那是别人送他的毕业礼物<br />
Mother...
母亲<br />
Am I any good?
我有优点吗<br />
Brave.
很勇敢<br />
韦科市 警察局 刑事法庭<br />
Can it happen to anyone?
谁身上都会发生吗<br />
Nobody talks about it.
没人谈论它<br />
Help me not to sass my dad.
让我别跟爸爸顶嘴<br />
Help me not to get dogs in fights.
让狗狗们别打架<br />
Help me be thankful for everything I've got.
让我学会感谢所拥有的一切<br />
Where do you live?
你住在哪儿<br />
Help me not to tell lies.
让我不再说谎<br />
Are you watching me?
你在看着我吗<br />
I want to know what you are.
我想知道你是谁<br />
I want to see what you see.
我想看你所见<br />
Come here.
到这来<br />
You're going to stand there and
你就站在这<br />
you're going to close this door quietly, 50 times.
把门轻轻关上 重复五十次<br />
Count it out.
数出来<br />
3 4 5
3, 4, 5,<br />
6 7 8
6, 7, 8<br />
You can't just take off the top.
不能只抓着上面<br />
You got to get them by the roots.
得连根拔掉<br />
Your mother's naive.
你们的母亲很天真<br />
It takes fierce will to get ahead in this world.
要想出人头地得有非凡的意志<br />
If you're good, people take advantage of you.
如果你太善良 别人就会利用你<br />
Every one of these top executives,
那些形形色色的高官<br />
you know how they got where they are?
知道他们是怎么坐到那位子的吗<br />
Floated right down the middle of the river.
从河中间漂下去<br />
Don't let anyone tell you there's anything you can't do.
别让人说有什么是你办不到的<br />
Don't do like I did, promise me that.
向我保证 别重蹈我的覆辙<br />
Dreamed of being a great musician.
我曾梦想成为一名伟大的音乐家<br />
I let myself get sidetracked.
却半途而废<br />
If you're looking for something to happen, that was it.
如果你想有所成就 就要坚定不移<br />
Life, lived it.
生活 就要活出精彩<br />
Job imagined he might build his nest on high.
约伯曾憧憬巢筑高树的人生<br />
That the integrity of his behavior
他坚信自己行事光明磊落<br />
would protect him against misfortune.
会远离不幸 得到善报<br />
And his friends thought mistakenly
他的朋友错误地认为<br />
that the Lord could only have punished
上帝之所以处罚他<br />
him because secretly he had done something wrong.
是因为他做了见不得人的事<br />
But no.
但事实并非如此<br />
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
不幸也会降临到好人身上<br />
We can't protect ourselves against it.
我们无法避免不幸<br />
We can't protect our children.
保护不了我们的孩子<br />
We can't say to ourselves, even if I'm not happy,
不能对自己说 就算我不快乐<br />
I'm going to make sure they are.
也要让孩子们开心<br />
We run before the wind,
我们御风奔跑<br />
we think that it will carry us forever.
以为风儿会一路相随<br />
It will not.
但它不会<br />
We vanish as a cloud,
我们如云般消散<br />
we whither as the autumn grass.
如秋草般枯萎<br />
And like a tree, are rooted up.
如树般被连根拔起<br />
Is there some fraud in the scheme of the universe?
在宇宙的宏图中 是否存在着尔虞我诈<br />
Is there nothing which is deathless?
是否存在着长生不老<br />
Nothing, which does not pass away?
是否有不朽般的存在<br />
We cannot stay where we are.
我们不能停滞不动<br />
We must journey forth.
必须勇往直前<br />
We must find that which is greater than fortune or fate.
我们得找到比财富和命运更重要的东西<br />
Nothing can bring us peace, but that.
除此之外 没什么能带来安宁<br />
Is the body of the wise man or the just, exempt from any pain?
理智与公正是否使人免受病痛的折磨<br />
From any disquietude, from the deformity
挣脱不安的困扰 远离残缺的遗憾<br />
that might blight its beauty from the weakness,
残缺可能会使美丽因虚弱而凋谢<br />
that might destroy its health.
使健康不再<br />
Do you trust in God?
你相信上帝吗<br />
Job too, was close to the Lord.
约伯也离上帝很近<br />
Are your friends and children, your security?
你的朋友 你的孩子 你的安全呢<br />
There is no hiding place
在这世上<br />
in all the world where trouble may not find you.
困扰无孔不入 无所不及<br />
No one knows when sorrow might visit his house,
无人知晓悲伤会何时来敲门<br />
any more than Job did.
约伯也不知道<br />
At the very moment everything was taken away from Job.
在那刻 约伯被剥夺了一切<br />
He knew it was the Lord who had taken it away
他知道 是上帝剥夺了这一切<br />
Return from the passing shows of time
往事一幕幕重现<br />
he thought that which is eternal.
他以为那就是永恒<br />
As he alone see God's hand,
他只看到上帝伸出<br />
who sees that he gives.
那给予的双手<br />
Or does not also the one see God's hand,
也许他没意识到<br />
who sees that he takes away.
那双手同样意味着收回<br />
Or does he alone see God,
也许他只看到上帝<br />
who sees God turn his face towards him?
那慈善的面庞<br />
Does not also he see God,
也许他没意识到<br />
who sees God turn his back.
那同样意味着拒绝<br />
He's a friend of mine.
他是我朋友<br />
The one who's after real estate in town.
在城里继承了笔房产<br />
Frank Johnson.
弗兰克·杰克逊<br />
Started out as a barber.
理发师出身<br />
He built something, big.
后来成就了番大事业<br />
Now you'd think he was the fourth person of the Holy Trinity.
你可能会觉得他是三位一体中的第四人<br />
They never talk about their money.
他们对自己的钱财闭口不谈<br />
Wrong people go hungry.
饿着的都是不该挨饿的人<br />
Die.
死去的都是不应牺牲的人<br />
Wrong people get loved.
幸福的都是不值得被爱的人<br />
The world lives by a trigger.
这是个急功近利的世界<br />
You want to succeed? You can't be too good.
想成功 就别太善良<br />
Hey there young fella, try my cornbread.
小伙子 尝尝我的玉米面包<br />
Do y'all want some butter, do you?
你们想来点黄油吗<br />
How about a pound of bread?
来一磅面包怎样<br />
You'll like this right? Okay? Come on.
这样站着 知道吗 快点<br />
Act like you're in trouble,
装出一副惨样<br />
you don't want to fight, you don't want any trouble.
你不想挨揍 你不想惹麻烦<br />
The minute you see him blink, crack him!
一看到他眨眼 就上去痛扁他<br />
Okay?
懂了吗<br />
Okay, come on, three quarters.
来吧 三局了<br />
Cover, you're going to cover, right?
防守 要懂防守 好吧<br />
Okay, here. Come on, nice, harder, nice.
打这里 不错 再用力点 不错<br />
That's a good right, let's see your left.
右手不错 看看左手怎样<br />
This is the most important thing.
这是最重要的事<br />
Okay? You come in this way, keep your guard up.
懂吗 就这样出拳 同时注意防守<br />
Hit me, come on, hit me. Come on, Jack? Hit me.
打我 快点 打我 杰克 打我<br />
Hit me, come on, come on!
打我 快点 快点<br />
Okay, here it is, hit me!
这里 打这里<br />
Come on, son, come on!
快点 儿子 快<br />
What are you doing?
你在干什么<br />
Wipe yourself off.
拍拍干净<br />
Left! Don't leave your tongue out, you're going to lose it!
左手 别把舌头伸出来 会被打爆的<br />
Left. Left. Right. Right.
左 左 右 右<br />
Left, harder.
左手 用力点<br />
Harder. Harder!
用力 用力<br />
Hit me, hit me. Come on, son, hit.
打我 打我 快点 儿子 打<br />
Give me something, show me what you got.
给我点颜色看看 让我看看你都学到了什么<br />
Come on, go on.
快点 继续<br />
One meal.
吃饭吧<br />
Leave the table.
下桌<br />
You too?
你也想下桌吗<br />
- You going to continue to defy me? - No, sir.
- 你想一直和我作对吗 - 没有 先生<br />
You're interrupting me, I wasn't done yet.
你打断我了 我还没说完<br />
Am I finished?
我说完了吗<br />
- Am I? - No.
- 说完了吗 - 没有<br />
Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢谢 陛下<br />
Makes up stories.
编造的故事<br />
Fortunate words.
花哨的字眼<br />
He says don't put your elbows on the table.
他说别把手撑到桌上<br />
He does.
自己却那样做<br />
Insults people.
辱骂人<br />
Doesn't care.
一点也不关心人<br />
I remember when you were born.
我还记得你出生的日子<br />
They wouldn't let me come home.
他们不让我回家<br />
Navy said an officer must be present for the laying of the cue.
海军长官必须在场指挥任务<br />
I had to launch.
我必须出海<br />
The next word is volcano.
下一个词 火山<br />
Next word is socket.
下一个 插座<br />
Please pass your answers to each other.
把你们的答案交换一下<br />
We're going to grade each others' papers now.
现在给对方评分<br />
No interruptions, please.
别开小差<br />
Come on, get your pencil out.
快点 把铅笔拿出来<br />
Sweetheart! Oh God, sweetheart!
宝贝 天啊 宝贝<br />
Honey!
我的宝贝<br />
格里斯之墓<br />
Was it bad?
死亡很痛苦吗<br />
Will you die too?
你也会死吗<br />
You're not that old yet, mom.
妈妈 你还没那么老<br />
Where were you?
你在哪儿<br />
You had a boy die.
你就这样带走了一个男孩<br />
Would anything happen?
世事无常吗<br />
韦科市 滴滴涕<br />
I can't see! I can't see!
什么都看不见 什么都看不见<br />
Why should I be good?
我为什么要做个好人<br />
If you aren't.
你都不是好人<br />
Thank you.
谢谢<br />
We're close.
快到了<br />
Why's this bare here?
为什么偏偏这里裸露着<br />
The grass won't grow under the tree.
树下不长草<br />
- It does at Kimbles. - They have a gardener.
- 吉伯斯家树下却长草 - 他们有个园丁<br />
They have money.
他们有钱<br />
Of course he inherited it.
当然是继承来的<br />
I don't want to hear one more word out of you,
在把活干完之前<br />
not until this is finished.
我不想听见你说任何话<br />
You're cropping that too close.
你种得太密了<br />
You're going to have to keep that water.
你得留点水<br />
Toskanini.
托斯卡尼尼<br />
Once recorded a piece 65 times.
为了一首歌 他就重录了65次<br />
You know what he said when he finished?
你知道他完成时说了什么吗<br />
It could be better.
没有最好<br />
Think about it.
好好想想<br />
27 patents, your father has.
你爸爸我有二十七项专利<br />
It means ownership, ownership of ideas.
它代表着占有 占有想法<br />
You gotta sew them up.
得好好利用它们<br />
- Get them by the nuts. - If you pardon my French.
- 疯狂地去占有 - 抱歉我语出不敬<br />
Be rich.
做个有钱人<br />
You make yourself what you are.
你能成为你想成为的人<br />
You have control of your own destiny.
你得掌握自己的命运<br />
Can't say I can't.
别说我不行<br />
You see I'm having trouble.
你看到我有麻烦<br />
I'm not done yet.
我还没完蛋<br />
Can't say I can't.
别说我不行<br />
Why's he hurt us?
他为什么要伤害我们<br />
Our father?
我们父亲<br />
- Come on, Vince! Come on. - Get it, get it!
- 来吧 文斯 快来 - 接住 接住<br />
Give your father a kiss.
来亲你父亲一下<br />
Lies.
谎言<br />
- I can't. - Will you do something for me?
- 我不能 - 你能帮我做件事吗<br />
Do you promise you'll do it?
你能保证按我说的做吗<br />
Without having to ask what it is?
什么都不要问<br />
Just have the confidence in what your father asks of you is right?
只需相信你父亲的要求是对的<br />
Yes, sir.
好的 先生<br />
In the next half hour, will you
在接下来的半小时里<br />
not speak unless you have something important to say?
除了要紧事 你能不能管好你的嘴<br />
What did you do today, my fine feathered friend?
你今天做了什么 我的小鹦鹉<br />
Sit on the front of your chair.
坐椅子的前部<br />
It's better for your posture. I read that in the paper.
这种姿势最好 我在报纸上看到的<br />
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?
这你是从莱德贝特先生那里买的吗<br />
Don't explain, just nod, yes or no?
别说话 点头就行 是还是不是<br />
Be quiet.
别出声响<br />
What did you say?
你刚说什么<br />
Please.
求你了<br />
Leave him alone.
别碰他<br />
Leave him alone!
Come here! Come here!
过来 过来<br />
Get up there!
站起来<br />
You turn my own kids against me.
你让我自己的孩子跟我作对<br />
You undermine everything I do.
你破坏了我做的一切<br />
How do you like it?
你觉得爽了吗<br />
Stop it!
停下来<br />
Stop.
别动<br />
- Where's Dad? - He's gone on a trip.
- 爸爸去哪了 - 出海了<br />
Get her! Get her!
抓住她 抓住她<br />
Help each other.
互相帮助<br />
Do not slam that screen door!
别使劲摔门<br />
Love everyone.
爱每一个人<br />
Every leaf.
每一片叶子<br />
Every ray of light.
每一束光线<br />
Our gift.
我们的礼物<br />
Shut up!
闭嘴<br />
- Watch out! - Watch out!
- 小心 - 小心<br />
- Go. - Go!
- 快走开 - 快走<br />
I say let's bust them.
不如把玻璃砸了<br />
Found a frog!
找到一只青蛙<br />
Lets go set it off in a sky rocket!
把它绑到冲天炮下面<br />
He's getting away!
他逃走了<br />
Get back! Get back!
退后 退后<br />
Did he go to the moon?
他是不是去月亮上了<br />
- Where is he? - Here he is.
- 他去哪儿了 - 在这里<br />
It was an experiment!
这是实验<br />
Why?
为什么<br />
Never do it again.
别再那么干了<br />
Promise?
你保证吗<br />
You want to tell dad?
你要告诉爸爸吗<br />
They're just trying to scare you.
他们只是想吓唬你<br />
Keep your ear there.
你听好了<br />
Things she got to learn.
她得吸取教训<br />
I gotta know stuff too.
我也一样<br />
They say you can't try stuff? They do!
他们说你不敢试 他们可不怕<br />
What do you need be afraid of?
你有什么害怕的<br />
You're afraid. I see it.
你在害怕 我看出来了<br />
Right here! Right here!
就是这里 就是这里<br />
I can't talk to you.
我不能告诉你<br />
Don't look at me.
别看着我<br />
Au revoir, story.
再见 故事<br />
Au revoir, dawn.
再见 黎明<br />
Put it in there.
放进来<br />
I trust you.
我信任你<br />
- You tired? - No. I never get tired.
- 你累了吗 - 不 我从来不会累<br />
- You did this morning. - No, I was just pretending.
- 你今早就累了 - 没有 我装的<br />
- You call me a liar? - No.
- 你说我是骗子吗 - 不是<br />
- I don't want to fight. - Afraid to?
- 我不想打架 - 你是害怕吗<br />
No, I just don't want to.
不 我只是不想<br />
- If I was to say you're scared, would you call me a liar? - No.
- 要我说你就是害怕 你说我是骗子吗 - 不是<br />
You're scared, aren't you?
你在害怕 对吧<br />
Quit it.
别玩了<br />
Come here!
过来<br />
No!
不<br />
I don't want to do anything you tell me to.
我不想听你发号施令<br />
I want to do what I want.
我只想做我自己想做的事<br />
What do you know? You let him run all over you.
你知道什么 你让他骑在你头上<br />
How do I get back?
我要怎么回去<br />
Where they are?
他们在哪里<br />
This one is heavy, you're going to need two hands.
这个很重 你得用两只手来拎<br />
- Careful now, you know what's that? - Chinese?
- 小心点 你知道那是什么吗 - 中文<br />
That's Chinese, that's very good, yes, it is.
中文 没错 就是中文<br />
Your father went all around the world. All the way to China.
你们父亲周游了世界 一直到了中国<br />
That's Pan Am Airlines,
这是泛美航空公司的<br />
that's what your father flew on.
你们父亲坐的就是他们的航班<br />
The entire bathroom was stainless steel.
整个浴室都是不锈钢的<br />
Even the wash basin.
甚至连洗脸盆都是<br />
I feel confident the deal is going through.
我相信事情进行得很顺利<br />
Nothing, forget it. I'll tell Molly to go to hell.
没什么 别管了 我会告诉莫丽让她去死好了<br />
That's from Germany.
那是从德国带回来的<br />
See that?
看见那个了吗<br />
Put that down, son.
把那个放下 儿子<br />
Can Taylor come over?
泰勒能过来吗<br />
Was your family not good enough for you?
这个家对你还不够好吗<br />
It's not going to take as long as last time?
还会像上次煮那么久吗<br />
Al dente.
要有嚼劲<br />
It's a subjective point, you know the difference?
这是主观观点 你知道有什么区别吗<br />
Subjective means it comes from your mind.
主观的就是说是你自己的见解<br />
It can't be proven by other people.
别人无法证明<br />
It's good to see you again. Let's go, boys.
很高兴再见到你 走吧 小伙子们<br />
There are things you can't do.
有些事你无能为力<br />
But there are things I can't do either.
有些事我也无能为力<br />
You're not to call me dad, you will call me father.
你以后不要再叫我爸爸 你要叫我父亲<br />
- But... - Do not interrupt!
- 但是... - 不要插话<br />
- But you did... - Don't interrupt!
- 但是你以前 - 不要插话<br />
It's your house.
这是你的房子<br />
You can kick me out whenever you want to.
你什么时候想要我滚我就得滚<br />
You'd like to kill me.
你巴不得宰了我<br />
Dad.
爸爸<br />
Why was he born?
他为什么会出生<br />
Please, God, kill him.
求你了 上帝 让他去死吧<br />
Let him die.
让他去死<br />
Get him out of here.
让他离开这个世界<br />
She only loves me!
她只爱我一个<br />
Defend O'Lord this thy child with thy heavenly grace.
我主 请以圣宠保护你的这个孩子<br />
That he may continue thine forever.
保佑他永受圣恩<br />
And daily increase in thy Holy Spirit more and more
日渐成长 圣灵赐福<br />
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom, Amen.
直至他去到你永恒的国度 阿门<br />
See something...
我看见些东西<br />
Put your finger over it.
把手指头放上来<br />
There.
那里<br />
Come on.
来吧<br />
What I want to do I can't do.
我无法从心所欲<br />
I do what I hate.
只能违心而行<br />
You can hit me if you want.
你要是想打我就打吧<br />
I'm sorry.
对不起<br />
You're my brother.
你是我弟弟<br />
What was it you showed me?
你给我看的是什么<br />
I didn't know how to name you sin.
我不知道怎么罗列你的罪孽<br />
But I'll say it was you.
但是我会说就是你<br />
Always you were calling me.
你总是呼唤我<br />
I wanted to be loved because I was great.
我希望有人爱我 因为我很棒<br />
A big man.
一个大男人<br />
I am nothing.
现在却一无所有<br />
Look, the glory around us.
看 我们周围的荣耀<br />
Trees and birds.
树木和小鸟<br />
I lived in shame.
我活在羞愧中<br />
I dishonored it all and didn't notice the glory.
我蔑视一切 忽视了荣耀<br />
A foolish man.
我是个愚蠢的人<br />
They're closing the plant.
他们要关闭工厂<br />
They gave me a choice.
他们让我选择<br />
No job.
要么失去工作<br />
Or transfer to a job nobody wants.
要么去做没人愿意做的活<br />
Father.
父亲<br />
I never missed a day of work.
我从未懈怠过一天工作<br />
Mother.
母亲<br />
Tithe every Sunday.
周日按时缴税<br />
Always you wrestle inside me.
你们的思想我永远无法断然接受<br />
Always you will.
也永远无法忘记<br />
You know, Jack, all I ever wanted for you was...
知道吗 杰克 我对你的希望不过是...<br />
Make you strong and, grow up and be your own boss.
变成一个成熟强大 能主掌自己命运的人<br />
Maybe I've been tough on you.
也许我对你太严格了<br />
I'm not proud of that.
对此我并不感到自豪<br />
I'm as bad as you are.
我跟你一样差劲<br />
I'm more like you than her.
我更像你 而不像妈妈<br />
It was about all I've done in life, otherwise I've drawn zilch.
那是我一生的全部 其余则一片空白<br />
You're all I have, you're all I want to have.
你是我的一切 你是我想要的一切<br />
My sweet boy.
我亲爱的儿子<br />
Are you just going to stand there like a bump on a log?
你要像个呆瓜一直在那站着吗<br />
The only way to be happy is to love.
想要收获快乐 只有去爱<br />
Unless you love,
只有去爱<br />
your life will flash by.
你的生命才不会一晃而过<br />
Do good to them.
对他们好点<br />
Wonder.
奇迹<br />
Hope.
希望<br />
Brother.
兄弟<br />
Keep us.
养育我们<br />
Guide us.
指引我们<br />
To the end of time.
直到时间的尽头<br />
Follow me.
跟着我<br />
I give him to you.
我把他交付与你<br />
I give you my son.
我把儿子交付与你<br />